Joey Chiao-Yin Hsiao

jcyhsiao@umich.edu • +1 (734) 730-0963 • http://joeyhsiao.info 4365 N. Quad, 105 S. State St., Ann Arbor, MI 48109, USA

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Computer-Supported Cooperative Work (CSCW), and Social Computing. I employ qualitative and quantitative research methods to investigate how location-based social applications, such as people-nearby applications, hybrid community applications, sharing economy applications, support newcomers in adapting to a new environment.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

Ph.D in Information

09/2015 - present (expected fall 2020)

Advisor: Dr. Tawanna R. Dillahunt

National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

M.S. in Computer Science

09/2010 - 06/2013

Advisor: Dr. Jane Yung-Jen Hsu

Moffett Field, CA, USA

Carnegie Mellon University (Silicon Valley Campus)
Visiting Scholar

07/2012 - 09/2012

Advisor: Dr. Ted Selker

National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan 09/2006 - 06/2010

B.S. in Computer Science

PUBLICATIONS

Peer-Reviewed Journal Articles

[J1] Hsiao, J. C.-Y. and Dillahunt, T. R. (2018). Technology to Support Immigrant Access to Social Capital and Adaptation to a New Country. *Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction*, Vol. 2, CSCW, Article 70. (acceptance rate: 25.6%).

Peer-Reviewed Conference Proceeding Papers

- [C5] Dillahunt, T. R. and Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2020). Positive Feedback and Self-reflection: Features to Support Self-efficacy among Resource-constrained Job Seekers. To appear in *Proc. of The ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems 2020 (CHI '20)* (acceptance rate: 24.3%).
- [C4] Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Moser, C., Schoenebeck, S., and Dillahunt, T. R. (2018). The Role of Demographics, Trust, Computer Self-efficacy, and Ease of Use in the Sharing Economy. In *Proc. of the 1st ACM SIGCAS Conference on Computing and Sustainable Societies (COMPASS '18)*, Article 37 (Presenter).
- [C3] Hsiao, J. C.-Y., and Dillahunt, T. R. (2017). People-Nearby Applications: How Newcomers Move Their Relationships Offline and Develop Social and Cultural Capital. In *Proc. of the 2017 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW '17)*, 26-40 (acceptance rate: 33%; Presenter).
- [C2] Rajan, R., Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Lahoti, D., and Selker, T. (2013). "Roger that!" The Value of Adding Social Feedback in Audio-mediated Communications. In *Proc. of IFIP TC.13 International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction 2013 (INTERACT '13)*, 471-488 (acceptance rate: 31%).
- [C1] Tsai, W.-C., Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Lee, H.-C., Huang, C.-H., Hu, J.-C., Liang, R.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2013). Designing a Reminiscence Aid in Personal Soundscape. In *Proc. of International Association of Societies of Design Research 2013 (IASDR '13)*, 5150-5160.

Posters, Workshop Papers, and Presentations

- [P8] Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2019) Fostering Immigrants' Trust in Online Local Social Exchange. Presented at The 22nd ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW '19), Doctoral Consortium (Presenter).
- [P7] Haimson, O. L., Semaan, B., Dym, B., Hsiao, J. C.-Y, Herron, D., and Moncur, W. (2019) Life Transitions and Social Technologies: Research and Design for Times of Life Change. Workshop at *The 22nd ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW '19)*.

Posters, Workshop Papers, and Presentations (Cont.)

- [P6] Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Dillahunt, T. R. (2017) Detecting Life Changes: Increasing Opportunities to Benefit from People-Nearby Applications. In Proc. of *The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2017 (CHI EA '17)*, 1700 1707 (Presenter).
- [P5] Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Pan, M.-H., Wang, H.-C., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2015) Let's Solve It Together: Introducing Crowd Workers to Friendsourcing for Improving Creative Design. Presented at *The Taiwan Computer-Human Interaction Workshop 2015 (Tai-CHI '15)* (Presenter).
- [P4] Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Pan, M.-H., Wang, H.-C., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2015). The Price of the Priceless: Understanding Estimated Costs of Work in Friendsourcing. In *The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2015 (CHI EA '15)*, 1893-1898 (Presenter).
- [P3] Tsai, W.-C., Lee, H.-C., Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Liang, R.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2013). Framing Design of Reminiscence Aids with Transactive Memory Theory. In *The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2013 (CHI EA '13)*, 331-336.
- [P2] Tsai, W.-C., Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Lee, H.-C., Huang, C.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2012). In Search of Lost Sounds: Designing a Reminiscence Aid in Everyday Soundscape. Presented at *The ACM conference on Designing Interactive Systems 2012 (DIS '12)*.
- [P1] Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Jih, W.-R., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2012). Recognizing Continuous Social Engagement Level in Dyadic Conversation by Using Turn-taking and Speech Emotion Patterns. Presented at AAAI '12 Activity Context Representation Workshop (ACR '12) (Presenter).

Unpublished Theses and Research Reports

- [U3] Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2018). Social Network Matters: Opportunities for Technologies to Support Immigrants' Jobseeking. Field Prelim, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan.
- [U2] Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2017). Can People-Nearby Applications Benefit Newly-Arrived Immigrants? An Exploratory Study. *Pre-candidacy research paper*, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan.
- [U1] Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2012). Assessing Engagement in Conversation by Hierarchically Decomposing Emotion and Interaction. *Master's Thesis*, Dept. of Computer Science and Information Engineering (CSIE), Natl. Taiwan Univ.

RECENT PROJECTS

Designing Social Technologies to Support Newly Arrived Immigrants' Adaptation

Project Leader

Summer 2016 - Present

Exploring socio-technical factors that affect recent immigrants' engagement in using social applications to interact with ethnically mixed user communities, and designing technology interventions that address these factors.

Designing Next-Generational Employment Tools for Underserved Job Seekers

Project Leader

Fall 2018 - Present

Designing, deploying, and investigating novel employment tools' influences on resource-constrained job seekers' job search.

Investigating Factors Influencing Participation in the Sharing Economy

Research Assistant

Fall 2017 - Spring 2018

Examining the effects of online trust, demographics, and digital literacy on people's participating in the digital sharing economy.

Discovering People-Nearby Applications' Potential Benefits for People who Face Life Transitions

Project Leader

Fall 2015 - Spring 2016

Studying how people who are new to an area use people-nearby applications' (PNAs) to develop social capital and what are the concerns associated to their use.

HONOR

Graham Sustainability Institute, University of Michigan

Description of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI, USA 2020

Dow Sustainability Doctoral Fellowship

Was granted \$15,000 for research on designing social technologies to support immigrants' adaptation and local communities' sustainability; Only ten UM doctoral candidates were granted with the fellowship.

University of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

Rackham Pre-candidate Research Grant

2016

Was granted \$1,500 for conducting research on the project that explores immigrants' social technology use for adaptation.

Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ.

Taipei, Taiwan

Graduation Representative

2012

Was chosen as the recognized master's student for leadership and active participation in student affairs of the department

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Social Innovations Group, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

Graduate Student Research Assistant

09/2015 - present

Lead research projects of the Social Innovations Group (SIG), which are focused on designing technologies to help low-resourced populations seek employment and education (Advisor: Dr. Tawanna R. Dillahunt)

UX Team, Intel-NTU IoX Center

Taipei, Taiwan

Workshop Organizer

03/2015 - 05/2015

Organized the collaborative workshop on design thinking of Stanford d.school and National Taiwan University IoX Center

Research Assistant

07/2014 - 07/2015

Carried out research on user experience and natural user interface under smart environment as the only M.S. member in the team (Advisor: Dr. Bing-Yu Chen)

Collaborative & Social Computing Lab, Dept. CS, Natl. Tsing-Hua Univ.

Hsinchu, Taiwan

Visiting Research Assistant

07/2014 - 07/2015

Led a project on friendsourcing, aiming to understand how social capital works when a SNS user requests resources on her/his own social network (Advisor: Dr. Hao-Chuan Wang)

Taiwan Army (Mandatory Military Service)

Taichung, Taiwan

Company Chief Consultant (Second Lieutenant)

08/2013 - 07/2014

Handled psychological consulting, human resources management, and welfare of a military company with 40+ members

Intelligent Agents Lab, Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ.

Taipei, Taiwan

System Administrator

03/2011 - 07/2013

Managed devices and web services for 30+ lab members

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

Academic Events & Activities

 $ACM\ Mobile HCI\ 2019$ 09/2017 - 10/2019

Student Volunteer Chair

Taiwan CHI 2015 01/2015 - 07/2015

Organizing Committee

OpenHCI Workshop 2014 (student-organized workshop on HCI in Taiwan) 01/2014 - 07/2014

Steering Committee

OpenHCI Workshop 2013 01/2013 - 07/2013

Program Chair

OpenHCI Workshop 2011 01/2011 - 07/2011

Registration and Volunteer Chair

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES (Cont.)

Social Events & Activities

Univ. of Michigan, School of Information

08/2018 - 07/2019

Doctoral Committee - Student Representative

First Taiwan Night at CSCW

2019

Organizing Committee

Annual Taiwan Night at CHI Organizing Committee 2015 - 2018

Reviewer

ACM CHI 2017 - 2020; ACM CSCW 2017, 2018, 2020; ACM MobileHCI 2018 & 2019; ACM TEI 2017

Conference Student Volunteer

ACM CSCW 2018, 2019; ACM COMPASS 2018; ACM CHI 2017

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant/Graduate Student Instructor

School of Information, Univ. of Michigan Winter 2018

SI-622: Usability Testing Instructor: Prof. Joyojeet Pal

School of Information, Univ. of Michigan Fall 2017

SI-501: Contextual Inquiry Instructor: Prof. Kentaro Toyama

Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ. &

Dept. Design, Natl. Taiwan Univ. of Tech. and Sci. Spring 2013

Advanced Human-Computer Interface/User-Oriented Innovation Design

Instructor: Prof. Hsien-Hui Tang & Prof. Mike Y. Chen

Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ. Fall 2011

Introduction to Computer Science Instructor: Prof. Jane Yung-Jen Hsu

Student Team Coach

OpenHCI Workshop 2011 07/2011

SPEAKING ENGAGEMENT

Invited Speaker School of Information, Univ. of Michigan

SI699: Mastery User Experience Research and Design 12/2019

Lightning Speaker Univ. of Michigan

iDEI: Talks at the Intersection of Information, Diversity, Equity & Inclusion 10/2018